

Divya Prakash

Nationality: Indian | Phone number: (+91) 7411405523 (Mobile) | Email address:

d.prakash0615@gmail.com | Website: https://dpfolio.tech | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/divyaprakashdp/ | WhatsApp Messenger: +917411405523

Address: Bengaluru, India (Work)

ABOUT ME

I am an experienced software engineer with over 4 years in building responsive applications, particularly in healthcare and e-commerce sectors. My expertise spans various programming languages and development frameworks. I am recognized for my problem-solving skills and ability to master new technologies. I thrive in collaborative environments and am committed to staying current with industry advancements

DIGITAL SKILLS

Docker | HTML | CSS | Javascript | ReactJS | MongoDB | NodeJS | Typescript | AWS | Redux | Kubernetes | Git | GraphQL | Agile Development | Jest | TDD

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/2020 - CURRENT Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER DELOITTE

- Building SSO and auth pages for an ecommerce client
- Developed scalable solutions using JavaScript and ReactJS, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement.
- · Thrived in diverse tech stacks, rapidly acquiring new skills to meet client requirements

08/2019 - 10/2020 Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER METRICSTREAM

- Revamped internal R&D tool which reduced the manual task by around 30%
- Developed an API validation tool.
- Proficiently utilized JavaScript, and node.js to deliver solutions

04/2017 - 08/2019 Bengaluru, India

SOFTWARE TESTER EMIDS

- Responsible for automating the test cases for an e-healthcare product
- · Worked on automating UI and REST APIs
- Kept quality at par by introducing CI/CD

PROJECTS

Polarix

A web clone of POSTMAN tool with some extra feature like AI enabled validation, better reports and bring your own database to save your collections and requests.

Link https://polarix.dpfolio.tech

Bibliai

An Al enabled book search, recommendation, summary and analysis app.

Link https://bibliai.dpfolio.tech/

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

07/2011 - 06/2015 Bhopal, India

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING Rajiv Gandhi Technical University

Level in EQF EQF level 6

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **HINDI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
GERMAN	A2	A2	A1	A1	A2
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user